<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Practical English</title>
    <link>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Practical English</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.practicalenglish.tk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Frozen - An Act of True Love: Video Lesson</title>
      <link>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/frozen-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/frozen-video/</guid>
      <description>Task description &amp;amp; scene summary Task description: The students are going to work with synonyms and improve their listening skills.
Scene summary: This scene shows Anna sacrificing herself for Elsa. Will it have a happy ending?
         Video URL https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r6OkgfPRCSI   Video length 3 minutes 1 second   Video genre Cartoon / tale for kids (e.g. Tom &amp;amp; Jerry, Simon&amp;rsquo;s cat, Peppa Pig, Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alice in Wonderland: Video Lesson</title>
      <link>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/alice-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/alice-video/</guid>
      <description>  Task description &amp;amp; scene summary Task description: practice the use of comparatives using the battlefield scene of Alice in Wonderland
Scene summary: Alice and the White Queen prepare for battle against the Red Queen and the Jabberwocky
         Video URL https://youtu.be/1WOVUUKenNA   Video length 4 minutes 22 seconds   Video genre Film scene (animated or live-action with human-actors)   Lesson type Grammar practice   Level Pre-intermediate (A2)   Student types adults   Copyright license Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial License   First published 2019-02-08, 00:04:45 (GMT+1)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Plastic Ocean: Video Lesson</title>
      <link>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/plastic-ocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/plastic-ocean/</guid>
      <description>Task description &amp;amp; scene summary Task description: A Plastic Ocean is a lesson plan from British Council Learning Teens that has been adapted.
Scene summary: Climate Change ( A Plastic Ocean). It&amp;rsquo;s a trailer in which a journalist shows how polluted our ocean is, due to plastic.
         Video URL https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6zrn4-FfbXw   Video length 2 minutes 9 seconds   Video genre Film trailer   Lesson type Deep listening comprehension - Meaning check (&amp;ldquo;Do you understand what it means?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Falls Down by Alan Walker: Music Video</title>
      <link>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/all-falls-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/all-falls-down/</guid>
      <description>Task description &amp;amp; scene summary Task description: Intermediate (B1) students are expected to unscramble sentences and correct any misused words.
Scene summary: A futuristic video. The lyrics are quite simple and easy to comprehend. Some curse words are used.
         Video URL https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6RLLOEzdxsM   Video length 3 minutes 41 seconds   Video genre Music video   Lesson type Basic listening comprehension - Hearing check (&amp;ldquo;Can you make out the words being said?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Great Conversation Starters: Video Lesson</title>
      <link>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/7-convo-starters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/7-convo-starters/</guid>
      <description>Task description &amp;amp; scene summary Task description: Pay attention to the use of indefinite pronouns such as: something, anything, everything, someone, etc.
Scene summary: A visual sketch tutorial about how to start a conversation and how to keep it alive.
         Video URL https://youtu.be/7zXLp01ZmV0   Video length 9 minutes 55 seconds   Video genre Tutorial, how-to video   Lesson type Basic listening comprehension - Hearing check (&amp;ldquo;Can you make out the words being said?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crow - The Legend: Video Lesson</title>
      <link>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/crow-the-legend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/crow-the-legend/</guid>
      <description>Task description &amp;amp; scene summary Task description: The students are going to improve their listening skills and work with prepositions after verbs.
Scene summary: Crow continues his journey, on his way home he saves Moth, but he accidentally puts out the fire.
         Video URL https://youtu.be/AO4PrtAKu2E   Video length 3 minutes 37 seconds   Video genre Cartoon / tale for kids (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prisoner of Azkaban: Video Lesson</title>
      <link>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/prisoner-of-azkaban/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/prisoner-of-azkaban/</guid>
      <description>Task description &amp;amp; scene summary Task description: Once again, students have to perform easy tasks of listening and comprehension, spot certain words in sentences.
Scene summary: Harry Potter and his friends are ready for a new adventure, which will inevitably come.
         Video URL https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ZdlAg3j8nI   Video length 2 minutes 9 seconds   Video genre Film trailer   Lesson type Basic listening comprehension - Hearing check (&amp;ldquo;Can you make out the words being said?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zootopia Verbs: Video Lesson</title>
      <link>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/zootopia-verbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/zootopia-verbs/</guid>
      <description>Task description &amp;amp; scene summary Task description: Select the correct verb in the sentence.Select the correct verb in the sentence.Select the correct verb in the sentence.
Scene summary: When Officer Judy Hopps arrives in Zootopia, she discovers that being the first bunny on a police force of big, tough animals isn’t so easy.
         Video URL https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TH3aHSxzKWY   Video length 0 minutes 58 seconds   Video genre Cartoon / tale for kids (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Job Interview: Video Lesson</title>
      <link>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/job-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.practicalenglish.tk/post/job-interview/</guid>
      <description>Task description &amp;amp; scene summary Task description: In this video quiz students fill in the missing past simple irregular verbs. 20 gapfill questions to practice grammar.
Disclaimer: Contains moments of nudity. It is your responsibility to consider if this is appropriate in your culture/educational setting.
Scene summary: An odd candidate shows up for a job interview only to find that the interviewers are even weirder than he is.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>